A Guide to the Papers of Rear Admiral Walter C. Ansel, 1924-1974
Special Collections and University Archives, Patricia W. and J. Douglas Perry Library, Old Dominion University
- Oversized Materials
  - The British Isles, National Geographic Society, 1949 (Oversize Oversize, Box 1)
  - Khania (Greece), First GSGS Army/Air Edition, 1947 (Oversize Oversize, Box 1)
  - Timbakion Pirgos, Greece, Reproduced by the Command and General Staff College, 1949 (Oversize Oversize, Box 1)
  - Germany and Its Approaches, National Geographic Society, 1944 (Oversize Oversize, Box 1)
  - World News Map, General Drafting Company, 1958 (Oversize Oversize, Box 1)
  - Chart of Pacific Ocean and Coastal Areas (2) (Oversize Oversize, Box 1)
  - Chart of North Atlantic Ocean and Coastal Areas (Oversize Oversize, Box 1)
  - Iraklion (East Crete), First GSGS Edition, 1943 (Oversize Oversize, Box 1)
  - Iraklion (West Crete), First GSGS Edition, 1943 (Oversize Oversize, Box 1)
  - Plans on the North Coast of Crete, U.S. Navy Hydrographic Office (2), 1951 (Oversize Oversize, Box 1)
  - Chart of Baltimore Harbor, U.S. Coast and Geodetic Survey, 1955 (Oversize Oversize, Box 1)
  - Iraklion Khania (Crete), Reproduced by the Command and General Staff College, 1947 (Oversize Oversize, Box 1)
  - Japan Taiwan (Formosa), From Japanese and British Surveys to 1930, Hydrographic Office Washington D.C., 1944 (Oversize Oversize, Box 1)
  - Calais, GSGS, published by War Office, 1943 (Oversize Oversize, Box 1)
  - City of Manila, Engineer Phil. Dept. U.S. Army, 1935 (Oversize Oversize, Box 1)
  - Amsterdam-Hamburg, GSGS (BAOR)(9), 1952 (Oversize Oversize, Box 1)
  - Bruxelles-Frankfurt a Main, GSGS (BAOR)(8), 1952 (Oversize Oversize, Box 1)
  - World Map, National Geographic Society, 1951 (Oversize Oversize, Box 1)
  - Great Britain, War and Navy Department, 2nd GSGS Edition (8), 1944 (Oversize Oversize, Box 1)
  - Chart of Chesapeake Bay, Cove Point to Sandy Point, U.S. Coast and Geodetic Survey, 1943 (Oversize Oversize, Box 1)
  - Japan-China, Stanford's Geog., London (Oversize Oversize, Box 1)
  - Hazebrouck (Belgium & N.E. France) GSGS, Published by War Office, 1942 (Oversize Oversize, Box 1)
  - Atlas of the German Campaign in France 1939-1940, reproduction dated 1950 (Oversize Oversize, Box 1)
  - London-Paris, GSGS, Published by War Office 1942, revised 1944 (6) (Oversize Oversize, Box 1)
  - Dover Patrol, Mines and Net Barrages, December 31, 1917 (Oversize Oversize, Box 1)
  - Bartholomew's Map of Europe and the Mediterranean, John Bartholomew & Son Ltd., May, 1941 (Oversize Oversize, Box 1)
  - Theater of War in Europe, Africa, and Western Asia, National Geographic Society, 1942 (Oversize Oversize, Box 1)
  - Landau & Karlsruhe (taped together) 2nd Edition Army Map Service, 1951 (Oversize Oversize, Box 1)
  - Top of the World, National Geographic Society, 1949 (Oversize Oversize, Box 1)
  - Northern France & Germany (London-Paris & Bruxelles-Frankfurt maps taped together) (Oversize Oversize, Box 1)
  - 3-Dimensional relief map of Crete "The Long Slinky Dragon" (Oversize Oversize, Box 2)
  - Iraklion, Army Map Service, 3-Dimensional relief map of East end of Crete, 1964 (Oversize Oversize, Box 2)
  - Khania, Army Map Service, 3-Dimensional relief map of West end of Crete, 1964 (Oversize Oversize, Box 2)
  - Outline Chart of the World, U.S. Navy Hydrographic Office, 1931 (Oversize Oversize, Box 2)
  - Philippine Islands, U.S. Coast and Geodetic Survey, 1933 (Oversize Oversize, Box 2)
  - Saronikos Kolpos and Kolpos Petalion, U.S. Hydrographic Office, 1958 (Oversize Oversize, Box 2)
  - Gulf of Mexico, Caribbean Sea including the West Indies, U.S. Hydrographic Office, 1925 (Oversize Oversize, Box 2)
  - Pacific Ocean, Western Part including Eastern Archipelago, U.S. Hydrographic Office, 1931 (Oversize Oversize, Box 2)
  - Indian Ocean, Northern part, U.S. Hydrographic Office, 1926 (Oversize Oversize, Box 2)
  - Cape May to Cape Hatteras, U.S. Coast and Geodetic Survey, 1942 (Oversize Oversize, Box 2)
  - North Atlantic Ocean, U.S. Hydrographic Office, 1927 (Oversize Oversize, Box 2)
  - Approaches to Baltimore Harbor, U.S. Coast and Geodetic Survey, 1944 (Oversize Oversize, Box 2)
  - Block Island Sound and its approaches, U.S. Coast and Geodetic Survey, 1930 (Oversize Oversize, Box 2)
  - Cape Hatteras to Charleston Light, U.S. Coast and Geodetic Survey, 1942 (Oversize Oversize, Box 2)
  - Chesapeake Bay, Severn, & Magothy Rivers, U.S. Coast and Geodetic Survey, 1948 (Oversize Oversize, Box 2)
  - Mediterranean Sea-Western sheet, U.S. Hydrographic Office, 1942 (Oversize Oversize, Box 2)
  - Chesapeake Bay, Patuxent River to Sharps Island, U.S. Coast and Geodetic Survey, 1942 (Oversize Oversize, Box 2)
  - Malta to Crete, including Ionian Sea, U.S. Hydrographic Office, 1958 (Oversize Oversize, Box 2)
  - Crete, Eastern part, U.S. Hydrographic Office, 1957 (Oversize Oversize, Box 2)
  - North Atlantic Ocean, Eastern Part, U.S. Naval Oceanographic Office, 1969 (Oversize Oversize, Box 2)
  - North Sea-Southern Sheet, U.S. Hydrographic Office, 1947 (Oversize Oversize, Box 2)
  - Hawaiian Islands, Oahu, U.S. Coast and Geodetic Survey, 1941 (Oversize Oversize, Box 2)
  - Hawaiian Islands, Oahu to Niihau, U.S. Coast and Geodetic Survey, 1933 (Oversize Oversize, Box 2)
  - Hawaiian Islands, Hawaii, U.S. Coast and Geodetic Survey, 1940 (Oversize Oversize, Box 2)
  - Pacific Ocean, U.S. Hydrographic Office, 1925 (Oversize Oversize, Box 2)
  - Ports de Marseille, U.S. Naval Oceanographic Office, 1969 (Oversize Oversize, Box 2)
  - Approaches to Marseille, U.S. Naval Oceanographic Office, 1969 (Oversize Oversize, Box 2)